Inventory of the Robert Morton Hughes Papers 1715-1933
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Robert Morton Hughes Papers, 1715-1933.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 H88
237 items.
Business and personal papers, 1871-1933 (mainly 1890-1915), of Robert Morton Hughes (1855-1940).
Frances Hodgson Burnett,; Marcus Alonzo Hanna ,; Oliver Wendell Holmes,; Robert Morton Hughes,; Joseph E. (Joseph Eggleston) Johnston,; Fitzhugh Lee,; Thomas Nelson Page,; Theodore Roosevelt,; Flora Cooke Stuart,; Sir Arthur Sullivan,; Mark Twain ,; Woodrow Wilson.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 237 items, 1940.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert Morton Hughes, an alumnus of the College of William and Mary, attended the University of Virginia Law School. He was the son of Robert William and Eliza M. (Johnston) Hughes. He practiced law in Norfolk, Virginia. Hughes was the president of the Virginia Bar Association; biographer of Joseph Eggleston Johnston; a member of the Virginia Board of Education; and served as a member and as rector of the Board of Visitors of the College of William and Mary.
Biography Timeline
1855 Born, in Abingdon, Virginia, the son of Robert William and Eliza M. [Johnston] Hughes
1870- 1873 Attended College of William and Mary, A.B.
1877 M.A., University of Virginia
1877 Began law practice in Norfolk
1879 Married Mattie Smith of Williamsburg(two sons)
1893-1918 Member of the Board of Visitors of the College of William and Mary, served as Rector
1895 President, Virginia Bar Association
1930- 1935 Member, Virginia State Board of Education
1940 Died in Norfolk, Virginia
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1871-1933, of Robert Morton Hughes of Norfolk, Virginia, concerning his law practice; his interest in maritime law; his biography of Joseph Eggleston Johnston; his influence in Virginia politics; and the College of William and Mary. Correspondents include Joseph Eggleston Johnston, Fitzhugh Lee, Sir Arthur Sullivan, Thomas Nelson Page, Woodrow Wilson, Flora (Cooke) Stuart and Theodore Roosevelt. There is also an autograph collection, 1715-1924, which includes signatures of Frances Hodgson Burnett, Mark Hanna, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr., Samuel L. Clemens and presidents of the United States.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection has been organized into 2 series: Series 1 includes Personal and Business Correspondence, and Series 2 includes an Autograph Collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series which are then broken down into subseries. Series 1 is arranged by date and Series 2 is arranged alphabetically.
Additional Related Materials
Related Materials at William And Mary
There are five collections within the Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary that relate to this collection. They include the John B. Floyd Papers, the Robert W. Hughes Papers, the Joseph E. Johnston Papers, the Preston Family Papers, and the Virginia Bar Examination Papers. The Library of Robert William Hughes is also available in the rare book section.
John B. Floyd Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
John Buchanan Floyd Papers, 1831-1863, 1850- 1863.72 items.Collection number: Mss. 65 F59
Robert W. Hughes, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Robert W. Hughes Papers, 1818-1900.103 items.Collection Number: Mss. 39.2 H87
Joseph E. Johnston Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Joseph E. Johnston Papers, 1825-1891.264 items.Collection number: Mss. 39.1 J63
Preston Family Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Preston Family Papers, 1755-1836.90 items.Collection Number: Mss. 39.1 P91
Virginia Bar Examination Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Virginia Bar Examination Papers, 1900- 1923.1,306 items.Collection Number: Mss. 39.1 V81ba
The library belonging to Robert William Hughes is located at the Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Related Materials at Old Dominion University
Another related collection is the Robert Morton Hughes Papers, located in Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University. This collection in significant because of the correspondence and other papers originally belonging to several of Hughes' relatives including Judge Robert W. Hughes, Governor John B. Floyd, and General Joseph E. Johnston. The collection also contains personal and political correspondence regarding Robert Morton Hughes' legal practice, involvement in Virginia politics, activities in support of education, longtime association with the College of William and Mary, and service on the State Board of Education and the Board of Directors of the Norfolk Public Library.
The William and Mary collection of Robert Morton Hughes Papers compliments and does not duplicate the Robert Morton Hughes Papers at Old Dominion University.
Papers of Robert Morton Hughes, Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University, Norfolk, Virginia. Papers of Robert Morton Hughes, 1767- 1959.39 Hollinger Flat Boxes; 5 Hollinger Oversized Boxes and Additional Bound Volumes.Collection number: MG-7
Controlled Access Terms
Persons:
Johnston, Joseph E. (Joseph Eggleston), 1807- 1891.; Lee, Fitzhugh, 1835-1905.; Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900.; Page, Thomas Nelson, 1853-1922.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Stuart, Flora Cooke.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1849- 1924.; Hanna, Marcus Alonzo, 1837-1904.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809- 1894.; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910.
Subjects:
Practice of law-- Virginia-- History.; Lawyers--Virginia--Norfolk.; Lawyers--Virginia-- Correspondence.; Autographs.; Virginia--Politics and government--1865- 1950.
Contents List
  Series 1: Personal and Business Correspondence
- Personal and business correspondence, 1871-1933, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-4)
  - Personal and business correspondence, 1871-1890., 16 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - L. B. Wharton, n.p., to B[enjamin] S. Ewell,[Williamsburg, Virginia?], 24 April ca. 1871., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Discusses and compares Floyd Hughes' mental capabilities to those of his brother [Robert M. Hughes], and how he would fare at the "University".
    - J. E. Johnston, Healing Springs, [Virginia], to "Rob" [Robert Morton Hughes], n.p., 1 September 1871., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Mention of the irregularity of mail in the southern states; is pleased that he and his brother, Floyd, will be enrolled at W[illia]m and Mary College[sic] at the same time; tells of an "old and valued" friend, Col. [Benjamin S.] Ewell, who is president of the College; he will mention to Ewell their presence at the College; assumes that their Cousin, Mrs. Munford, will also be available for help; is pleased that he has "been applying [himself] to Modern Languages."
    - S[amuel] S[ullivan] Cox, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, n.p., 27 November 1876., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Regretfully refusing position as Orator of the Washington and Jefferson Literary Societies of the University of Virginia.
    - Rob[er]t Desty, St. Paul, Minnesota, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, n.p., 26 December 1882., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Would appreciate Hughes' proofreading his second edition of Shipping & Admiralty.
    - John B. Minor, Law Department, University of Virginia, [Charlottesville, Virginia], to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 20 August 1883., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Concerning admiralty cases.
    - Tho[ma]s J[ohn] Morris, U.S. Court House, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 6 October [18]84., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Concerning thanks for work done.
    - Irving Browne, Albany Law Journal, Albany, New York, to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 18 February 1886., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Is returning Hughes' article as it cannot be published for several weeks.
    - W[illia]m C. Endicott, War Department, Washington City [D.C.], to John W. Daniels [sic][Daniel], House of Representatives, [Washington, D.C.], 29 April 1886., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Concerns a copy of the report of the Board on Fortifications or other Defenses Endicott wished sent to R. M. Hughes.
      Including ANS from Jo[h]n W. Daniel, n.p., to [?], 30 April 1886, requesting that the report be forwarded to Hughes. 1 page.
    - Hugh L[ennox] Bond, Balt[im]o[re], [Maryland], to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia], 1 May 1887., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Acknowledges invitation if visiting Norfolk.
    - L[unsford] L[omax] Lewis, Richmond, Virginia, to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 28 February 1888., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Accepts invitation to visit.
    - Geo[rge] R[eed] Sage, District Judge, United States Courts, Judges' Rooms, Cincinnati, Ohio, to Robert W. Hughes, U.S. District Judge, Norfolk, Virginia, 13 October 1888., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Concerning the trial of Directors of the Glasgow Bank. Including an ANS from Ro[bert] W. Hughes, n.p., to Robby [Robert M. Hughes], n.p., n.d., directing him to respond to Judge Sage's letter. 1 page
    - D[av]id Dudley Field, New York, [New York], to Rob[ert] M. Hughes, n.p., 9 November 1889., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Discusses various tax reforms in different states, including Connecticut and New York, and how they are faring.
    - Eppa Hunton, Washington, D.C., to R. M. Hughes, n.p., 24 January 1890., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Concerning case of Harris Rogers vs. Garland Johnston & others.
    - Ro[ber]t T[homas] Barton, Winchester, Virginia, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, n.p., 30 April 1890., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Regrets that he will not be attending the meeting of the [Virginia] Bar Association this year because he will be getting married.
    - R[obert] E[noch] Withers, Wytheville, Virginia, to Rob[ert] M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 6 October 1890., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Accepts invitation to be present at the laying of the corner stone of the Market and Connory Building on the centennial anniversary of Norfolk Lodge No. 1.
    - Marcus J[oseph] Wright, [Washington, D.C.?], to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., ca. 1890., 1 page. Written on printed circular from the War Department. ALS. (Box-folder 1:1)
      Asks Hughes to loan the government any Confederate Papers he knows of for the official government publication of the records of the Civil War.
  - Personal business and correspondence, 1891-1900., 20 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Dabney H. Mowry, Richmond, Virginia, to R[obert] M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 17 March 1891., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Concerning Gen. Johnston's papers and his biography.
    - Bradley T. Johnson, Baltimore, [Maryland], to R. M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 20 May 1891., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Concerning a memoir of General Joseph E. Johnston.
    - Tho[mas] Preston, University of Virginia, [Charlottesville, Virginia], to Robert M. Hughes, Jnr.[?], Norfolk, Virginia, 21 July 1891., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      As Hughes requested, sends a report of what he saw and did at the first battle of Manassas.
      Including AMsS by Tho[ma]s L. Preston, University of Virginia, [Charlottesville, Virginia], n.d., giving report of "first battle of Manassas." 13 pages.
    - Philip A[lexander] Bruce, Richmond, Virginia, to R. M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 17 December 1892., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Acknowledges receipt of a copy of Hughes' address delivered at the College of William and Mary.
    - Ja[me]s Grant Wilson, Association of American Authors, New York, [New York], to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 8 October 1893., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Congratulates Hughes on favorable reviews of his biography of Joseph E. Johnston.
    - [William] Mahone, Hotel Chamberlin, Washington, D.C., to Ro[bert] M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 6 November 1893., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Acknowledges receipt of Hughes' life of J.E. Johnston.
    - Rob[ert] P. Dick, Greensboro, North Carolina, to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 28 November [18]93., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Acknowledges receipt of copy of Hughes' college address. Has sent it to the University of North Carolina Library.
    - Fitzhugh Lee, Glasgow, Virginia, to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 22 February 1894., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Concerning Hughes' biography of Gen. Johnston, and issues surrounding the writing and publishing of a "Life of Lee".
    - P.W. Mc Kinney, Governor's Office, Richmond, Virginia, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, n.p., 20 January 1895., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Has received his letter of the 19th; refers to controversy surrounding the Board of Visitors of the College of William and Mary; holds him in high esteem.
    - John A. Buchanan, Conference Room of the Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia, Wytheville, Virginia, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 15 June 1895., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Hughes' letter of request for the Board of Trustees of E[mory] & H[enry] College was not received before they adjourned; therefore, it was not considered.
    - W[illia]m B. Taliaferro, Ware Neck P.O., Gloucester County, Virginia, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 20 August 1895., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Congratulates Hughes on his recent election as President of the Bar Association of Virginia.
    - N[athan] Goff, Clarksburg, West Virginia, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 12 December 1895., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Enclosing the order in the libel case; the report "connecting my name with the nomination to political office, is without my sanction..."; and expressing appreciation of your kind offer.
    - Rich[ar]d A. Wise, Williamsburg, Virginia, to R. M. Hughes, n.p., 30 October 1896., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Requests Hughes to make a speech.
    - James A. Walker, Washington, D.C., to R[obert] M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 14 April 1897., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Requests that a letter be written to President McKinley asking him to appoint Henry Bowen[?] of Tazewell to Marshall of the Western District of Virginia.
    - Sir Arthur Sullivan, [London, England], to [Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia], 23 August [18]97., 2 pages. Copy. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Card formally acknowledging receipt of verses sent by Hughes and declining to set them to music.
    - Charles H[enry]Simonton, U.S. Court Rooms, Charleston, South Carolina, to R[obert] M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 29 October [18]97., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Discusses a problem with Professor Graves of the Law School.
    - W[illia]m L[yne] Wilson, Washington & Lee University, Lexington, Virginia, to Ro[bert] M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 5 March 1899., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - W[illiam] J[ames] Bryan(for committee), H. C. Tobey and R. H. Watson, Washington & Lee University, Law Department, Lexington, Virginia. to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 31 March 1899., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Concerning thanks from senior law class for a highly interesting course of lectures.
    - Tho[ma]s Nelson Page, Chicago, [Illinois], to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 7 November 1899., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Concerning an invitation to speak before the Phi Beta Kappa at Williamsburg; and Page's attempt to secure a church for his brother to serve in as a preacher in the area near his home.
    - Woodrow Wilson, Princeton, New Jersey, to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 17 December 1900., 2 pages. TLS. (Box-folder 1:2)
      Discusses the ceremony used in conferring degrees at Princeton.
  - Personal and business correspondence, 1901-1910., 17 items. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Alex[ander] P[eter] Stewart, Chattanooga, Tennessee, to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 10 June 1901., 1 page. ACS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Asks for a copy of the biography of Gen[eral] Jos[eph] E. Johnston.
    - Molly Elliot Seawell, Washington, D.C., to [Robert M.] Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia], 22 May 1902., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Requests Hughes' assistance in obtaining a position in the Norfolk post office for her niece, Ellen Seawell.
    - James Keith, Wytheville, Virginia, to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 8 June 1902., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Glad that Hughes agrees with them on the sufficiency of just two examinations.
    - Worthington C. Ford, The Library of Congress, Washington, D.C., to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 24 December 1902., 1 page. AL (Box-folder 1:3)
      Returning a manuscript of William Campbell which was repaired at the Library.
    - Flora Stuart, n.p. to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., [May 1903]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Acknowledges receipt of Hughes' life of J. E. Johnston and speaks of General J. E. B. Stuart's relations with him. Encloses some papers, "culled from many."
      Including an ANS from J. E. B. Stuart, near Gainesville, [Virginia], to [Flora (Cooke) Stuart], n.p., 25 June 1863, stating that "All well on the warpath." 1 page.
    - Claude A. Swanson, Governor of Virginia, Governor's Office, Richmond, [Virginia], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 23 March 1906., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Appoints Robert M. Hughes a member of the Board of Visitors of the College of William and Mary in Virginia for a two-year term.
    - William E[velyn] Cameron, Louisa, Virginia, to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 28 March 1906., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Sends printers proofs of a newspaper article written by Cameron which mentions Hughes's father.
    - Theodore Roosevelt, The White House, Washington, [D.C.], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 19 May 1906., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Concerning Hughes' biography of General [Joseph E.] Johnston.
    - James Barr Ames, Law School of Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 12 June 1906., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Sorry he missed Hughes' son's call, and hopes he "will give me the chance of making his acquaintance."
    - A[drian] H[offman] Joline, New York, [New York], to R. M. Hughes, n.p., 7 May 1907., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Concerning a method of preserving autograph letters and documents.
    - Frederic Dodge, United States Courts, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 27 November 1907., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Thanking him for a copy of "Maritime Liens."
    - William F. Hamilton, Kensington Gore, S. W., [London, England], to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 20 December 1907., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Thanking him for a monograph on maritime liens.
    - Frederic Dodge, United States Courts, Boston, [Massachusetts], to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 10 February [19]08., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Returns to Hughes his letter of the 27th, and suggests that it would be better not to have it published.
    - C. A. Culberson, United States Senate, Washington, D.C., to Robert M. Hughes, Law Building, Norfolk, Virginia, 1 April 1909., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Thanks Hughes for his kind invitation, but has to decline due to the vast amount of work needed to be done on the proposed tariff revision; also discusses a newly elected Senator from Mississippi, [John Sharp] Williams, whose term doesn't begin until 4 March 1911, due to the fact that the Legislature of Mississippi convenes only every four years.
    - John S. Williams, Yazoo City, Mississippi, to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 5 April 1909., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Declines an invitation.
    - H. G. Connor, U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals, Richmond, Virginia, to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 27 November [1909]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Thanks Hughes for his monograph, and will try to secure a copy for himself.
    - Thomas T. Munford, Lynchburg, Virginia, to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 2 August 1910., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Desires information about John B. Floyd for a paper on the seals and flag of Virginia.
  - Personal and Business Correspondence, 1911-1933, n.d., 19 items. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Robert W. Chambers, [New York, New York], to R. M. Hughes, Jr., Norfolk, Virginia, 25 January 1911., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Gives title of certain volume, and who published it.
    - James Bryce, British Embassy, Washington, [D.C.], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 28 Sept 1911., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Discusses the various legalities relating to suit being filed under the Arbitration Agreement.
    - H. M. Alden, Editorial Rooms, Harper's Magazine, New York, [New York], to Robert M. Hughes, n.p., 22 January 1912., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Returns two letters of Gen. Joseph E. Johnston which were submitted for publication.
    - H. C. Lodge, United States Senate, Committee on Private Land Claims, [Washington, D.C.], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 27 January 1915., 1 pages. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Thanks Hughes for his letter relating to the maintenance of actions for death on the high seas; doubts that Senate will act on it this session due to most of their time being spent on the ship purchase bill.
    - Elihu Root, United States Senate, Washington, [D.C.], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 28 January 1915., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Acknowledges letter of 22 January with enclosure, and promises to give it due consideration.
    - Claude A. Swanson, United States Senate [Washington, D.C.], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 28 January 1915., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Acknowledges receipt of Hughes' views on pending legislation.
    - H. Berg, Newport News, [Virginia], to R. M. Hughes, Jr., Norfolk, [Virginia], 28 February [19]16., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Acknowledges receipt of a card to admit him to the privileges of the Virginia Club at Norfolk.
    - Prince Hotzfeldt, German Embassy, Washington, D.C., to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 8 April 1916., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Encloses letter of German Ambassador [Count Bernstorff] to Lt. Hans Berg.
      Including a TLS from Count Bernstorff, German Embassy, Washington, D.C., to Lieutenant Hans Berg, S. M. S. Appam, Newport News, Virginia, 8 April 1916, containing copies of the communications sent to and received from the Foreign office of the German Government at Berlin by the Imperial German Embassy at Washington, Concerning the Appam case. 3 pages.
    - W[illia]m S. Sims, Newport, Rhode Island, to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 13 January 1917., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Thanking him for document sent.
    - Ian Malcolm, British Embassy, Washington, [D.C.], to Robert M. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 21 May 1917., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Thanking him for pamphlets sent.
    - Arthur James Balfour, Geneve, Suisse, to [Robert M.] Hughes, n.p., 30 August 1921., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Concerning arrival of biography of General Joseph E. Johnston.
    - John W. Davis, n.p., to Rob[er]t M. Hughes, n.p., 22 July 1924., 1 page. TLS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Thanks Hughes for his letter.
    - H. C. Stuart, Elk Garden, Virginia, to Robert m. Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia], 23 July [19]24., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:4)
      Relates to the addition of General Joseph E. Johnston to the group to be memorialized at Stone Mountain, [Georgia].